WHY PHP?
We decided to use PHP since we have used PHP before, so we are more familiar with it and its running environment compared to Node.js. Our previous experience can help us improve our work in our current web applications. In addition, PHP is relatively easier to learn and yet still is a powerful enough platform for our purposes. Assistance is everywhere (older platform, so more resources compared to node) and deployment is simple. 
WHY NOT NODE?
We chose PHP over Node.js because it has a steep learning curve and isn’t ideal for novice developers. It’s a relatively young platform as well, so we have less resources online to refer to. Node.js is hosting is hard compared to PHP, and too troublesome for our liking. Overall, we think that node.js is too complex for our purposes and PHP fits what we want to do with our application.
